<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
      xmlns:opds="http://opds-spec.org/2010/catalog">

<title>Demo Publications Repo</title>
  <author>
    <name>Matthias Bock</name>
  </author>

<entry>
    <title>Understanding the role of host hemocytes in a squid Vibrio symbiosis using transcriptomics and proteomics</title>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Collins</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tyler R. Schleicher</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bethany A. Rader</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Spencer V. Nyholm</name>
    </author>
    <dc:language>en</dc:language>
    <dc:issued>2012</dc:issued>
    <summary>
	The symbiosis between the squid, Euprymna scolopes, and the bacterium, Vibrio fischeri,
	serves as a model for understanding interactions between beneficial bacteria and ani-
	mal hosts. The establishment and maintenance of the association is highly specific and
	depends on the selection of V. fischeri and exclusion of non-symbiotic bacteria from the
	environment. Current evidence suggests that the host’s cellular innate immune system, in
	the form of macrophage-like hemocytes, helps to mediate host tolerance of V. fischeri. To
	begin to understand the role of hemocytes in this association, we analyzed these cells by
	high-throughput 454 transcriptomic and liquid chromatography/tandem mass spectrome-
	try (LC-MS/MS) proteomic analyses. 454 high-throughput sequencing produced 650, 686
	reads totaling 279.9 Mb while LC-MS/MS analyses of circulating hemocytes putatively
	identified 702 unique proteins. Several receptors involved with the recognition of microbial-
	associated molecular patterns were identified. Among these was a complete open reading
	frame to a putative peptidoglycan recognition protein (EsPGRP5) with conserved residues
	for amidase activity. Assembly of the hemocyte transcriptome showed EsPGRP5 had high
	coverage, suggesting it is among the 5% most abundant transcripts in circulating hemo-
	cytes. Other transcripts and proteins identified included members of the conserved NF-κB
	signaling pathway, putative members of the complement pathway, the carbohydrate bind-
	ing protein galectin, and cephalotoxin. Quantitative Real-Time PCR of complement-like
	genes, cephalotoxin, EsPGRP5, and a nitric oxide synthase showed differential expression
	in circulating hemocytes from adult squid with colonized light organs compared to those
	isolated from hosts where the symbionts were removed.These data suggest that the pres-
	ence of the symbiont influences gene expression of the cellular innate immune system of
	E. scolopes.
    </summary>
    <link rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail"
          href="thumbnail.php?filename=Understanding the role of host hemocytes in a squid Vibrio symbiosis using transcriptomics and proteomics.pdf"
          type="image/png"/>
    <link rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" 
          href="publications/Understanding the role of host hemocytes in a squid Vibrio symbiosis using transcriptomics and proteomics.pdf"
          type="application/pdf"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
